Sia: Pipsqueak!
Sia: Stay out of my way!
Sia: Or else!
text: #02 THERE WAS A FORMIDABLE FOE
DEEP INSIDE THE DEN
Sia: Not deep enough!
Ario: Wow.
Sia: You over there!
Sia: If you can move,
now's your chance to escape!
Lock: Ario, Ginny, run for it!
Ario: Y-Yeah!
Ginny: Okay!
Ario: Lock?!
Lock: Watch for surprise goblin attacks.
Ario: Let's go, Ginny!
Ginny: R-Right!
Lock: You saw that you'd only
get in the way here.
Lock: Well done, Ario.
Lock: Want some help?
Sia: Huh?! Didn't you run away?
Lock: There's no need for me to run.
Sia: Do what you want, then!
Sia: But I don't need you jumping in!
Lock: Hm...
Lock: Say, you're currently losing.
Sia: Are you saying I'm weaker
than this underling?!
Lock: No, I'm talking about your sword.
Lock: See?
Lock: You sure you don't want help?
Sia: Just follow your friends,
and get out of here!
Lock: I'm done asking.
Lock: I'll just take him down.
Sia: You?!
Lock: You... make too much noise.
Lock: Were you hurt?
Sia: Who the hell...
Sia: I mean, who are you, sir?
Sia: Pardon me, sir.
Sia: I am Sia, daughter of Danton,
Sia: the chieftain of
the Eastern Beastkin Tribe.
Sia: I am grateful that you
rescued me from danger.
Sia: And you are?
Lock: An F-rank adventurer who was passing by!
Sia: You lie! Sir.
Lock: Check it.
Sia: Y-You really are F-rank?!
Lock: I know, right?
Sia: Why are you so proud
of being F-rank, sir?
Sia: Besides, that strength
was abnormal for an F-rank.
Lock: It's a long story.
Lock: What's your rank, Sia?
Sia: I am B-rank, sir.
Sia: But now, it feels terribly rude for me
to tell you to run away back there.
Sia: I'm ashamed of myself, sir.
Lock: You only did that because
you thought I was a beginner.
Sia: W-Well, yes, sir...
Lock: For an adventurer,
that was the right call.
Lock: I'm Lock.
Lock: A veteran F-rank adventurer.
Sia: What does that even mean, sir?
Lock: By the way, what lurks
deeper inside here?
Lock: Isn't there a much bigger fish here
than a goblin lord?
Sia: Wh-Whatever could you mean?
Lock: Earlier, you called the
goblin lord an underling.
Lock: That means there's a stronger enemy.
Sia: Well, I mean...
Lock: You don't have to tell me
if you don't want to.
Sia: Hey! Where are you going, sir?!
Lock: I was contracted to exterminate goblins.
Lock: But if there's a bigger threat than that,
Lock: I have to keep going for the sake
of nearby villages.
Lock: And I'll defeat it.
Sia: This won't be a foe
that's so easy to defeat, sir.
Sia: We're up against... a vampire lord!
Lock: Aha, a vampire lord.
Lock: Abnormally high vitality.
Transforms into bats, or mist.
Lock: That's a troublesome opponent indeed.
Lock: Isn't that a lot for you to handle, Sia?
Sia: Wh-Why is that, sir?
Lock: Well, a mere goblin lord gave you trouble.
Sia: Even so, sir, I can't afford to run away!
Lock: Fine, but don't get hurt.
Sia: You aren't going to ask why?
Lock: Do you want me to ask?
Sia: No.
Lock: Then I won't.
Sia: Our tribe has hunted
vampires for generations.
Lock: She's telling me anyway?
Sia: A while ago, we were fighting vampires,
Sia: and we had them down to just one.
Sia: But after my father, the chieftain,
was badly wounded,
Sia: we ended up letting it get away.
Sia: That one escapee...
Lock: ...was, of all things, a vampire lord.
Sia: It was my tribe's failure
that it escaped, sir.
Sia: It's my duty as chieftain's daughter
to restore my tribe's honor!
Sia: I've been pursuing him for months,
Sia: and now I finally know where he is!
Lock: Is it against the rules for someone
Lock: to help you beat him
and restore your tribe's honor?
Sia: No, sir. It will be restored
even if I receive help.
Lock: Good, then.
Sia: But I still think
you should go back, Lock.
Lock: You can't fight without a weapon.
Lock: I'll let you borrow this.
Sia: Huh? Th-Then what will you use?
Lock: I'm powerful even barehanded!
Sia: Thank you, sir.
Sia: He's telling me to be the one to
strike down the vampire lord.
Sia: That's why he's bluffing
about fighting barehanded.
Lock: Looks like that's the end of them.
Sia: Y-You really are strong
even unarmed, sir!
Lock: Aren't I?
Lock: Well, I'm originally a sorcerer.
Lock: I used to be with Eric and Goran,
who were abnormally strong,
Lock: so I was stuck firing off magic from
the rear, but I was still S-rank.
Lock: Also, I spent ten years fighting
a demon horde and the Demon King,
Lock: so my martial arts
improved in a mad hurry.
Lock: Well, what say we attack
that throne room?
Sia: Y-Yes, sir!
Vampire Lord: Hmph. So the little puppy girl
tries to reach above her station.
Sia: You shut up!
Sia: You're cornered now, vampire lord!
Sia: I swear I'll take you down myself!
Vampire Lord: When it took all your father
could muster to even scratch me?
Vampire Lord: You, defeat me?
When you're weaker than him?
Vampire Lord: Don't be ridiculous.
Vampire Lord: Think again, girl.
Vampire Lord: For baring your fangs at me,
the lord of the night,
Vampire Lord: regret will be the last feeling
you ever have!
Lock: I get it now.
Lock: You must have been making
the goblin pack look small
Lock: so you could lure adventures down here.
Vampire Lord: Well, well. You're apparently
not a complete fool.
Vampire Lord: You qualify to be my servant.
Vampire Lord: But puppy, I must commend you
for bringing a human along.
Sia: Huh?
Sia: My Vampiric Charm
won't work on a mere beast.
Sia: But I can use it to turn
a human into my servant.
Sia: Oh no!
Sia: Lock, run for it!
Vampire Lord: It's too late!
Sia: L-Lock...
Vampire Lord: Come here.
Sia: This was entirely my mistake.
Vampire Lord: Dog girl.
Vampire Lord: Choose. Will you die by my hand, or his?
Sia: Huh?
Vampire Lord: N-No! Why didn't it work?!
Lock: Because I have a high resistance
to mental debuffs.
Vampire Lord: Get real!
Vampire Lord: A mere human could never withstand
a vampire lord's Vampiric Charm!
Lock: Then you must not be a vampire lord.
Lock: Maybe you're a lesser vampire
who's convinced he's a vampire lord.
Sia: H-He sure is poking the bear.
Vampire Lord: H-How dare you?!
Sia: Look out!
Lock: You're darn quick for a lesser vampire.
Vampire Lord: You'll pay...
Vampire Lord: You shall pay dearly!
Vampire Lord: You'll rue the day you mocked me!
Sia: That's... a high-level magic circle!
Lock: Super Speed.
Lock: Drain Touch!
Vampire Lord: Th-This spell is...!
Lock: You're good at absorbing life force,
Lock: but not at having it taken
from you, lesser vampire!
Vampire Lord: Who the hell are you?
Lock: Lock, the F-rank adventurer.
Vampire Lord: Stop messing with me!
Vampire Lord: Fine, then.
Vampire Lord: But don't forget,
you have provoked my wrath!
Vampire Lord: Never again will you
spend a peaceful night!
Lock: Typical bloodsucker bluster.
Sia: You won't escape!
Vampire Lord: Wha?! I-I can't regenerate!
Vampire Lord: By destroying me...
the medallion's already...
Lock: Looks like that came in handy.
Sia: Thank you, sir.
Sia: The blade is so sharp.
Sia: And I felt some kind of power
well up when I sliced him.
Lock: Y-You must have imagined it.
Lock: I can't tell her it's
the Demon King's sword.
Lock: What're you doing?
Sia: Oh! Found it, sir!
Lock: What is it?
Sia: A cursed medallion, found inside
the bodies of special vampire lords.
Lock: Cursed medallion?
Sia: When a vampire lord with one of these
inside sucks blood or kills someone,
Sia: a curse builds up in the medallion.
Lock: These weren't around ten years ago.
Lock: Are they a new fad with vampires?
Vampire Lord: Defeating me will bring you no peace!
Vampire Lord: The medallion's power will soon open
a portal to the dimensional rift!
Lock: Dimensional rift?
Vampire Lord: That's right.
Vampire Lord: Once the portal opens, countless demons
will surge forth and overrun this world.
Vampire Lord: And from the other dimension
shall come our dark gods!
Sia: Dark gods?
Lock: The dimensional rift.
Lock: That's where, until recently,
I'd been fighting for ten years.
Lock: We don't know how to open
a portal to it from this side.
Lock: A decade ago, we fought
the Demon King on our side,
Lock: and when he fled into
the dimensional rift,
Lock: we leaped in before the portal closed.
Lock: It's usually an exit-only affair.
Lock: That's why Eric and Goran were unable
to come help me once they'd left.
Vampire Lord: Live in terror until
the advent of the dark gods!
Vampire Lord: Many vampire lords will be drawn to that
medallion, and eventually one will—
Vampire Lord: Y-You absorbed the curse?!
Lock: Even if a dimensional portal
does open, no demons will come.
Lock: Because I already kicked all their asses.
Vampire Lord: That sword...
Vampire Lord: The Demon King's sword...
Vampire Lord: You... You couldn't be...
Vampire Lord: the Great Sage Lu—
Sia: L-Luck? Great Sage Luck?
Lock: Sorry I cut up the medallion.
Sia: Oh, no problem if it's
in two pieces, sir.
Lock: Ario and Ginny are probably
worried, so let's hurry.
Sia: Are you sure those two
are all right, Luck?
Lock: They're fine.
They're both great, for F-ranks.
Sia: I said "Luck" when I asked
you just now, not "Lock."
Sia: Sir, are you the Great Saint Luck?
Lock: It's a secret.
Sia: Yes, sir!
I will guard your secret with my life!
Lock: No need to be that determined.
Sia: Now that I look again,
Sia: you do look like
Great Saint Luck's statue.
Lock: Huh? No, I don't!
Lock: Goblin gems.
Arone: It's good to see you safe and sound...
Arone: but how did you get so many?!
Ginny: The pack was bigger than expected.
Ario: Sia the B-rank adventurer happened to
be there to help us exterminate them.
Arone: The guild should have
assessed this job more accurately.
Arone: We apologize!
Sia: Looks like the guild's
going to do something
Sia: about the vampire lord incident, too.
Lock: Okay.
Lock: What're you doing?
Ario: Oh, Lock. You should thank
Great Sage Luck, too.
Ario: His protection was part of why
we safely completed this job.
Ginny: He's also the one who gave us
this time of peace.
text: HEE HEE
Ario: See ya, Lock.
Ginny: Let's team up again if we get the chance.
Lock: Sure.
Sia: Thank you again, Lock.
Sia: Now I can redeem my tribe's honor.
Lock: Hey, quit thanking me.
Lock: By the way,
Lock: would you mind sharing
the vampire info your tribe learns?
Sia: No problem, sir!
Lock: I'm not about to let the peace we've
defended for ten years just come undone!
Sia: Stare.
Lock: What?
Sia: I told you, Lock.
You do look like the Luck statue.
Lock: Enough of that, already.
Sia: Understood, sir.
Sia: You can speak directly with
Lord Morton, can't you?
Lock: Lord Morton?
Lock: Oh, you mean Goran.
Sia: I'd like you to urge Lord Morton
to be on the look out for vampire lords.
Lock: Didn't you report it to the guild?
Sia: Yes, sir.
Sia: But it's possible it'll be too late
Sia: once they verify the story
and relay it to the guildmaster.
Lock: I follow.
Sia: Lock.
Sia: Take this.
Lock: You sure?
Sia: I'm fine having just half of it,
Sia: and wouldn't it be best to have proof
when you explain to Lord Morton?
Lock: Okay. I'll hang on to it.
Sia: Right, sir!
Sia: I'll go straight back to my
village and gather information!
Lock: Sure!
Lock: Guess I'll go bring Goran up to speed.
Goran: What gives?!
Goran: Who says they're going out for "a bit"
and comes back three days later?!
Goran: Of course I'd worry!
Lock: Hey, it was just three days.
Goran: Just three days, but three whole days.
Goran: If you're gonna be out late,
drop me a line about it first!
Lock: Who are you, my mother?
Lock: Listen, something important has come up.
Goran: What's that medallion?
Lock: We could be in some trouble.
Goran: That's what they're planning?
Lock: Who'd have thought the demons
and even the Demon King
Lock: were just a vanguard for the dark gods.
Goran: I'd like to have a specialized agency
investigate this medallion.
Goran: Mind if I borrow it?
Lock: Sure, go for it.
Goran: Wonder what it's made of.
Lock: It looks like gold, but it isn't.
Goran: Doesn't seem to be orichalcum
or mithril, either.
Goran: Even you can't tell, as a sorcerer?
Lock: Unfortunately, no.
Lock: Maybe an alchemist could figure it out.
Lock: Well.
Lock: Time for me to get some sleep.
Goran: Lock.
Lock: Huh?
Goran: Thank you for protecting
those rookie adventurers.
Goran: I mean that as guildmaster.
Lock: Think nothin' of it.
Lock: Good night.
Lock: Yow!
Goran: Celliss, good timing.
I'd like to introd—
Lock: Who's she?
Goran: My daughter Celliss.
She's almost fifteen.
Lock: Ah! The one you said might have forgotten
what you look like, back in the rift.
Lock: Does she not like me or something?
Goran: No, she's avoiding me.
Goran: I was against her desire
to become an adventurer.
Lock: Why're you against it?
Goran: Parental bias aside, the fact is,
she's got B-rank ability.
Lock: Why, then?
Goran: But she's still a child.
Goran: She lacks the insight and
wariness an adventurer needs.
Lock: Don't you get those through experience?
Goran: I'd like to get my wife's input on this,
Goran: but she's on a trip
to a neighboring country.
Lock: Oh, okay. I guess
being a father's not easy.
Goran: Lock, I need a favor.
Lock: She definitely did inherit
her dad's talent.
Goran: Once Celliss is fifteen,
Goran: she won't need parental consent
to register as an adventurer.
Goran: At this rate, she might just go do so,
and then start adventuring.
Goran: When the time comes, could you
casually keep an eye on her?
Lock: Keep an eye on her?
Lock: She's the one glaring holes into me.
maid: Lady Celliss,
how much bread would you like?
Celliss: Three pieces, please.
Lock: Uh, can I help you?
Celliss: You...
Celliss: You're Papa's illegitimate child,
aren't you?!
Credits: TRANSLATION: DUANE JOHNSON
Credits: TIMING: EDGAR CRUZ
EDITING: ZACHARY CARLYSLE
Credits: QUALITY CONTROL: GABRIELLA ALABANZA
TRANSLATION CHECK: SRIRAM GURUNATHAN
text (top): NEXT TIME: SHE SUSPECTS I'M HER BASTARD BROTHER,
AND NOW WE'RE GOING ON HER FIRST ADVENTURE